ortholite.com 2018-11-11

# Privacy Statement - OrthoLite - High Performance Comfort Insoles - Open-Cell Foam Technology - Footwear Brands

ORTHOLITE (hereinafter also referred to as “we” or “us”) is responsible for the collection and processing of your personal data that we receive from you in connection with the use of our website. By accessing or using this website or other ORTHOLITE service on any computer, mobile phone, tablet, console or other device (collectively, “Device”), you consent to our privacy policy.

## Information Collected

**Information that is not collected:** your telephone number, your name, and your email and physical address

**Information that is automatically collected:** we may automatically collect information regarding your interaction with, and use of, our products and services. Information we may collect includes, but is not limited to, device identifier and hardware information, IP address, location (GPS) information, browser type and language, cookie information, system type, whether you have enabling software to access certain features, access times, referring website URLs, information about your purchases and other information about your interactions with us. This data primarily collected for statistical purposes for measuring and enhancing the functioning of the Site.

Certain information obtained on ORTHOLITE by means of cookies can be found in our Cookie Policy Statement available [here](http://www.ortholite.com/about/cookie-policy).

## Information from Third Parties

We may combine information you give us with other information from ORTHOLITE sources, transactions and communications. This may include, but is not limited to, information from direct mail, events, products and applications including social networking sites, or other ORTHOLITE interactions. We may also combine that information with data that is publicly available and data from third parties.

## Purposes of Personal Data Processing

We may use your information to enhance, customize and personalize your ORTHOLITE experiences and communications. We also use information to operate, provide, improve and maintain ORTHOLITE's products and services, including analyzing user behavior and trends. Additionally, we may provide and conduct marketing and promotions by communicating with you about our products, services and events, and for other promotional purposes; administer contests, promotions, events, surveys or other features; and display relevant marketing to you. Finally, we may also use data about how you use ORTHOLITE to prevent or detect fraud, abuse, and violations of our Terms of Use and to comply with court orders or applicable law.

## Legal Basis for Processing

We will collect and process your personal data for the purposes described in the section above on one of the following legal bases under the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR):

Article 6.1(a): Where your specific consent is required for the processing of your personal data as described herein, your personal data will be processed based on such consent.

Article 6.1(f): The processing is necessary for the purposes of our legitimate interests or other third parties' legitimate interests, and such interests are not overridden by your interests or fundamental rights; The legitimate interests that we pursue include our interest to answer to your specific requests, to ask your feedback in order to improve our Site and our products, or to pursue other general marketing activities.

## Retention Periods for Personal Data

Personal data is not kept for longer than the time necessary to achieve the specific data processing purposes described herein, unless shorter or longer retention periods apply under applicable law.

## Protecting your Personal Data

In order to protect information, we use a variety of security measures, including encryption and authentication tools, to help protect your information. However, ORTHOLITE cannot guarantee 100% the security or confidentiality of the information you provide to us.

## Recipients of Personal Data

We may transfer your information to ORTHOLITE service providers to conduct our business. For example, your information may be transferred to a third party as a part of our business assets in a sale of a part or all of ORTHOLITE. If this should happen, a notice will be provided by posting to the website or other form of communication. In addition, we may disclose information upon governmental request, in response to a court order, when required by law, to enforce our policies, or to protect our or others' rights, property or safety. We may share information to prevent illegal uses of ORTHOLITE's products and services or violations of the Terms of Use, or to defend ourselves against third-party claims. We may also share information with companies assisting in fraud protection or investigation.

## Site Elements Controlled by Third Parties

This Site contains links to other sites, as well as objects or elements controlled by third parties.

An example are plug-ins that may connect ORTHOLITE to social networks like Facebook or Twitter and are usually identified by the relevant social network's logo. If you interact with a social plug-in on our Site, your browser may send such social network certain data relating to you, such as your user ID, information on the Site, date and time, and other browser-related information. Such information will be processed by the social networks according to their privacy policies.

We have no control over how third party websites process your personal information. We do not review third party websites and disclaim any responsibility for such websites. You should check the privacy policy of third party websites to understand their processing of personal information.

## Transfers of Personal Data

Your personal data may be transferred outside of the country from which it was originally collected. The personal data we process will be stored in the USA. Some of the data recipients with whom OTHOLITE shares your personal data may be located in countries other than the country in which your personal data was originally collected. The laws in those countries may not provide the same level of data protection compared to the country in which you initially provided your data. Nevertheless, we will protect that personal data as described in this Policy and in compliance under applicable law.

## Your Rights

Data protection law gives rights to individuals regarding the personal data that websites obtain.

Providing personal data for survey, marketing and other profiling purposes as above specified is optional. We will require prior consent before processing your personal data for such purposes. Where such data is processed for marketing purposes, you have the right to object at any time to the processing of personal data. [See cookies policy](http://www.ortholite.com/about/cookie-policy)

### Right to access

You have the right to obtain confirmation as to whether your personal data is being processed and for what purpose. ORTHOLITE will provide a copy of personal data, free of charge.

### Right to be forgotten (Data Erasure)

You have the right to request ORTHOLITE to erase personal data in certain circumstances as defined under applicable law.

### Right to withdraw consent

If you have declared your consent for any personal data processing activities as described in this Privacy Statement, you can withdraw this consent at any time with future effect. Such a withdrawal will not affect the lawfulness of the processing prior to the withdrawal. Please note that withdrawal of certain contents may limit functions of the website or online services.

You have the right to object to the use or processing of your data at any time.

In case you have a complaint about the processing of your personal data, you have the right to lodge a complaint with a competent supervisory authority.

If you wish to avail yourself to the above rights, please send us an e-mail at: [info@ortholite.com](mailto:info@ortholite.com)

## Communications

Regardless of the settings you select, ORTHOLITE may send you service-related communications. To unsubscribe and stop receiving messages, please change your settings or follow the instructions in the email, text message, notification or other message type. If you have unsubscribed from any ORTHOLITE communications, due to production schedules, you may receive communications already in production.

## Children’s Privacy

We do not knowingly collect or solicit personal information from children under 13. We also encourage parents and other guardians to surf the Internet together with their children.

## Applicable Law and Jurisdictions

Massachusetts state law governs the interpretation of this Privacy Statement and applies to claims for breach of them regardless of conflict of laws principles. Both parties consent to exclusive jurisdiction and venue in courts sitting in Boston, Massachusetts. Both parties waive all defenses of lack of personal jurisdiction and forum non conveniens.

## Changes to This Online Privacy Statement

ORTHOLITE adheres to the principles of privacy and data protection. We may update this Privacy Statement as needed to reflect changes in the applicable law. When we post changes to this Privacy Statement, we will revise the "last updated" date at the bottom. If there are material changes to this Privacy Statement or in how ORTHOLITE will use your personal information, we will notify you by prominently posting a notice of such changes prior to implementing the change. We encourage you to periodically review this Privacy Statement to remain informed of how ORTHOLITE is protecting your information.

## How to Contact Us

If you have any questions, comments, or concerns regarding how we handle your personal data, you may contact us by e-mail at [info@ortholite.com](mailto:info@ortholite.com) or further contact information [here](http://www.ortholite.com/contact)
